Mike North: 所以这些是顶级类型，可以保存任何值。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So those are top
types that can hold any values.
让我们看看底部类型。
Let's look at bottom types.
所以这里有一个永远不会。
So here's a never.
所有底部类型都不能保存任何值。
Never, and all bottom types,
can hold no values.
一个常见的地方，你会看到它正在逐渐变窄。
And a common place you'll see
this is narrowing exhaustively.
所以我们有一个值 x，我们把它看作一个字符串或数字。
So we've got a value x and we're
regarding it as a string or a number.
因为编译器太聪明了，所以我必须在这里进行强制转换,
I just have to cast here because
the compiler's too clever,
即使我想把它变成一个字符串或数字，它也会说，这是一个字符串。
even if I tried to make it a string or
a number, it would say, that's a string.
你已经初始化了它。
You've initialized it.
但这就是我想要得到的。
But that's all I'm trying to get here.
所以我有一个条件
So I have one condition here for
字符串大小写，数字大小写的一个条件。
the string case, one condition here for
the number case.
你们可以看到，x 是一个字符串。
And you can see here, x is a string.
在这里，x 是一个数，在这里，x 是一个从不。
Here, x is a number and
down here, x is a never.
什么都没有了。
There's nothing left.
这是打字稿告诉你，如果你对你的类型很好,
This is TypeScript telling you that
if you've been good about your types,
你永远也到不了这里。
you can never get here.
迈克 · 诺斯: 所以你可能会在那里遇到一个。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So
that's where you might encounter one.
你不会创建类型为 never 的值，但是
You're not going to be creating
values of type never, but
在这里你会看到一个。
this is where you'll see one.
这是同样的例子，但是
So this is the same example but
看看我们能不能利用”永不”。
we're gonna see if we can
use never to our favor.
为此，我要创建一个新类型的错误，我想要一个子类错误。
And for this, I'm gonna create a new
type of error, I wanna a subclass error.
并调用这个 unreableerror。
And will call this UnreachableError.
这需要一个从来没有作为一个争论。
And it's gonna take
a never as an argument.
唯一可以输入 check against 的东西
The only thing that can type check against
这个 never 参数是一个 never 类型的值。
that never argument is
a value of type never.
这就是底层型的意思。
That's what it means to be a bottom type.
字符串不匹配，数字也不匹配。
A string won't match it,
a number won't match it.
然后，当然，我们接受一个信息
And then of course, we take a message and
我们在做了一些字符串插值之后传递它。
we kind of pass it along after
doing some string interpolation.
所以，和我们上面的例子一样。
So, same example as we had above.
只不过我把它改成了一个数字。
Except I've just changed this to a number.
它不会真的影响任何事情。
It doesn't really affect anything.
这就是我们的字符串箱，我们的数字箱。
So we've got our string case,
our number case.
在这里，你永远不会。
Down here, y is never.
这里开始变得很酷了。
Here's where this starts to get cool.
如果我给这个变量加上，它可能是布尔值的可能性。
If I add to this variable the possibility
that it could be a boolean.
我们在这里得到一个类型错误。
We get a type error down here.
因此，在创建这个子类的时候，在尝试使用 y 和
So, in creating this subclass of error and
in trying to take y and
确保它是一个永远不会在最后的 else 条款,
ensure that it is a never down
at that last else clause,
我实际上是在断言所有的条件,
I am effectively asserting
that all of the conditions,
所有的可能性都已经考虑好了。
all of the possibilities
are already taken care of.
为什么应该是一个从来没有到这一点？
Why should be a never by this point?
所以如果我有一个像这样的大交叉类型，这会提醒我。
So this would alert me if I had
a big intersection type like this.
我开始为它增加可能性，增加新的可能性。
And I start adding possibilities to it,
adding new things that this could be.
这在编译时告诉我，现在您有未处理的案例。
This at compile time is telling me,
now you have unhandled cases.
你必须加入这样的东西。
You've gotta go in and
add something like this.
迈克 · 诺斯: 哦，现在我们又没事了。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Ooh, and
now we're okay again.
因为现在，在这里，你回来了，再也不会。
Because now, down here,
y is back to never again.
这就是我们所说的穷举转换或穷举条件转换,
This is what we call an exhaustive
switch or an exhaustive conditional,
它同样适用于 if else 和 case switch。
and it works equally well with if else and
with case switch.
它确保我们在达到最后一个条款之前处理好一切事情。
It ensures that we handle everything
before we reach that last clause.
在大小写切换中，你会把它放到默认子句中，对吗？
And in a case switch, you would put
this in your default clause, right?
这是我写的几乎每一个打字应用程序中的另一个东西,
This is another thing that is in almost
every TypeScript app that I write,
无法反应的错误。
UnreachableError.
这一点，以及我的定义。
That, and IsDefined.
如果我在一个荒岛上而你只给了我几个打字稿函数,
If I was in a desert island, and you gave
me only a couple TypeScript functions,
是的，这些应该是最重要的。
these would be high on the list, yes.
学生: 所以它不会编译，所以它永远不会进入
&gt;&gt; Student: So wouldn't it just not
compile so it would never get into
错误因为为什么-Mike North: 问得好。
UnreachableError because why is-
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Excellent question.
学生: 你是怎么进入 unacableerror 的？
&gt;&gt; Student: How do you get
into UnreachableError?
迈克 · 诺斯: 很好，很好的问题。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Excellent,
excellent question.
有几种方法，第一，你可以做一些选角。
There are a couple of ways, one,
you could have done some casting.
你可以通过某种方式削弱你的性格让他们对你撒谎,
You could have weakened your types in
such a way that they're lying to you,
你可能会死在那里。
and you could end up there.
只是因为打字稿在那个代码点说，这是一个字符串数组。
Just because TypeScript at that point of
code says, this is an array of strings.
在你的程序中其他地方所做的恶作剧可以使它变成这样
Shenanigans that were done elsewhere
in your program can make it so
这不是一个字符串数组。
that's not really an array of strings.
所以这是一种方法。
So that's one way.
另一种方式，特别是如果你正在写一个图书馆,
Another way,
especially if you are writing a library,
消费者不一定使用你的类型信息。
you'll have consumers that are not
necessarily using your type information.
所以，如果我在一个函数中有这个，并且我把 y 当作一个参数
So, if I had this in a function and
I was taking y as an argument, there's
没有什么能阻止人们传递布尔值，或者数组，或者其他东西。
nothing stopping someone from passing
a boolean in, or an array, or whatever.
请记住，打字稿是一个编译时唯一的东西。
Remember, TypeScript is
a compile time only thing.
它在运行时不进行这些检查。
And it's not doing these
checks at run-time.
所以当你开始构建某个东西的时候,
So by the time you make your built
version of something and start going,
所有的检查都不存在了。
all of that checking is
not present anymore.
说实话这花了我不少时间,
That took me a while, to be honest,
当我第一次开始使用打字稿时,
when I first started using TypeScript
to able to delineate between,
这是运行时类型检查还是编译时类型检查？
is this a run-time type-checking thing or
a compile time type-checking thing?
另一个是 HTTP 响应。
Another one is HTTP responses.
我希望能够打印检查，因为他们来了，但
I'd love to be able to type
check those as they come in but
已经不存在了。
TypeScript is not there anymore.
所以，无论你做什么，都有可能泄露出来。
So, no matter what you do, there is
the possibility of that stuff leaking in.
这就是为什么当我们看到这些类型的警卫,
Which is why when we look at
these type guards or like,
我们之前看到的定义。
IsDefined, which we
were looking at before.
我们希望确保该功能的实现
We want to make sure that
the implementation of that function
是我们希望创建的类型保护的运行时等价物。
is the run-time equivalent of the type
guard that we wish to create.
对，这种类型的 x 并不是未定义的，它们很好地排列在一起。
Right, that type of x is not undefined,
that lines up very nicely.
但是你可能会有一个不太正确的类型守卫。
But you could have a type
guard that's not quite right.
这样你就很容易达到这个目标。
And that would very easily
allow you to reach this.
这正是您希望抛出异常的地方
And that's exactly where you want
an exception to be thrown so
你可以去解决这个问题，追踪你是如何到达那里的。
that you can go and address that and track
down how you could have gotten there.
学生2: 是的，所以这有点像我所处的环境
&gt;&gt; Student2: Right, so
it's kind of like in the environment of my
编写打字稿，这是不可能的。
TypeScript compilation,
this is never gonna happen.
但是如果我们把它捆起来，扔到野外，它就可以。
But if we bundle it up, throw it
out there into the wild, it could.
这就是我们要抛出错误的情况？
So that's the case where we're
going to throw the error?
迈克 · 诺斯: 你走对路了。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: You're on the right path.
我只是想软化它打字稿告诉你,
I would only soften it,
TypeScript is telling you,
这是不可能的，只要你对自己喜欢的类型完全诚实。
it's never gonna happen, as long as you've
been totally honest about your types.
您所依赖的所有库的类型信息都是完美的。
The type information for
all libraries you depend on is perfect.
你的类型守卫是以一种完全正确的方式实现的。
Your type guards are implemented
in a totally correct way.
其中一些是很难得到100% 的检查分数。
And some of these are really
hard to get 100% check marks on.
但是让我们把它和另一种方法比较一下，让我移除这个布尔值。
But let's compare it to an alternative,
and let me remove this boolean.
让我们把它和其他东西比较一下。
Let's compare it to something else.
如果我们只想处理字符串和数字，我们可以这样做。
If we just intended to handle strings and
numbers, we could have just done this.
但是你永远不会发现这些小小的不协调
But you're never going to find out
about these little incongruities, and
你想知道他们在那里，这样你就可以去解决他们。
you want to know that they are there so
you can go and address them.
根据类型，这种事情是不应该发生的，但是
It's something that according to
the types should never happen, but
实际上，这种情况时有发生，你想给自己留点面包屑。
in practice it happens and you want
to leave yourself some breadcrumbs.
我把它叫做这里，这几乎是一个很棒的 JavaScript 场景
I would call this here,
this is almost as great a JavaScript scene
作为 try catch 中的空 catch 子句。
as an empty catch clause in a try catch.
您可能会出现类型错误。
You're swallowing a type error,
potentially.
因为在这里，没关系，我可以加任何我想加的东西。
Because here, it doesn't matter,
I could add whatever I want.
没有线索，到处都没有线索。
No clues, no clues anywhere.
这个会直接掉下去的。
This is gonna fall straight through.
所以有一个彻底的转换是很好的。
So it's nice to have an exhaustive switch.
这是针对那些具有高度安全性的语言，比如 Rust。
And this is for languages that feature
a high amount of safety, like Rust.
它们有详尽的开关和
They have exhaustive switches and
在编程语言中构建了详尽的条件句。
exhaustive conditionals built right
into the programming language.
所以在 JavaScript 的目标定位中加入这个特性真的很不错。
So it's really nice to have this feature
in a JavaScript targeting thing.